Raymond Pearl Papers ca.1895-1940 Mss.B.P312
American Philosophical Society
Raymond Pearl Papers
Circa 1895-1940
Mss.B.P312
American Philosophical Society
19.25 Linear feet
Raymond Pearl spent the majority of his academic career (1918-1940) at Johns Hopkins University, where he was Professor of Biometry and Vital Statistics and Director of the Institute of Biological Research. Founder of the Quarterly Review of Biology and Human Biology, he made significant contributions in the areas of biology, genetics, eugenics, and statistics. The Pearl Papers includes correspondence as well as notebooks, scrapbooks, diplomas, photographs, and 33 volumes of diaries. There is significant correspondence with his wife, Maud (ca. 500 letters), and mother, Ida May (ca. 300 letters), particularly for the years 1895-1934. Of special note is Pearl's correspondence with his friend, colleague, and fellow Baltimoreian, H. L. Mencken (ca. 500 letters). The collection contains important information on the American Association of Physical Anthropologists, The Baltimore Sun, the Birth Control Federation of America, Dartmouth College, the International Institute of Statistics, Johns Hopkins University, and the National Academy of Sciences.
Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940
Bibliography
There is a biographical memoir in APS Year Book 1940.
African American History Note
Pearl's opposition to eugenics earned him both friends and adversaries (most notable among the latter, E. M. East), as reflected throughout the Pearl papers. His correspondence with East, Herbert Spencer Jennings, Karl Pearson, the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Ira Jewell Williams, Edwin B. Wilson, F. A. E. Crew, the Rockefeller Institute, and William T. Howard (among others) touches frequently on issues of genetics, eugenics, race, and human evolution. The correspondence with the N.A.A.C.P. comprises three folders of materials for the years 1927-1936, primarily concerning a study of Harlem Hospital.
Physiology, Biochemistry, and Biophysics Note
Scholars of physiology, biochemistry, or biophysics may find the following items of interest:
Lillie, Frank Rattray, 1870-1947 Correspondence (13 items) 1902, 1920-1939 English
Loeb, Jacques, 1859-1924 Correspondence (24 items) 1900-1923 English
Other Finding Aids note
The printed version of Bentley Glass' A Guide to the Genetics Collections of the American Philosophical Society contains another biography of Pearl and a further description of the Pearl Papers.
Separated Materials note
Photographs are housed with graphic materials.
Related Archival Materials note
A significant quantity of Pearl correspondence appears in the papers of Charles B. Davenport (239 items) and Herbert Spencer Jennings (278 items).
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Acquired, 1973.
Scope and Contents note
A major resource for study of American biometry in the first half of the 20th century, the Pearl Papers contain 14 linear feet of the professional correspondence of Raymond Pearl, longtime professor at Johns Hopkins University, 1.5 linear feet of correspondence with his mother, and one linear foot of letters from Pearl to his wife Maud, concentrated in the period before their marriage, 1897-1899. The Pearl Papers are a rich resource for study of the development of population genetics and population biology during the 1920s and 1930s, as well as biological statistics and biometry, and they contain valuable information on both eugenics and birth control.
The collection is divided into six series:
Series I Correspondence, 1895-1940 30 boxes; 15 linear feet
Series II Correspondence with Ida May Pearl, 1895-1934 2 boxes, 1 linear foot
Series III Correspondence with Maud Pearl, 1901-1929 3 boxes; 1.5 linear feet
Series IV Bound volumes, 1902-1940 43 vols.; 1.5 linear feet
Series V Photographs, 1897-1940 15 items, 0.25 linear feet
Series VI Certificates, 1903-1940 2 folders; 0.25 linear feet
Biographical/Historical note
An early and influential advocate for the importation of statistics into biological analysis, Raymond Pearl was a pioneer in American population biology and ecology. The son of Frank Pearl, a grocery clerk and shoe factory foreman, and Ida May McDuffee, Pearl attended Dartmouth College (A.B., 1899) and the University of Michigan (Ph.D., 1902). Like many students of his generation, Pearl traveled abroad after receiving his doctorate to strengthen his education, studying first at the University of Leipzig in 1905, and then under Karl Pearson at University College London (1905-1906). It was Pearson who quickened Pearl's interests in quantitative analysis and fostered his first efforts to apply statistics to population genetics. He married Maud Mary Dewitt, a fellow student at Michigan, and long his collaborator, in 1903.
Pearl's first academic appointments upon returning to the States were as an instructor of zoology at the University of Pennsylvania (1906-1907) and as chair of the Department of Biology at the Maine Agricultural Experiment Station (1907-1918). Befitting his position in Maine, Pearl was engaged primarily in applied research in the genetics of poultry and cattle. Through studies aimed at increasing the productivity of egg-laying in chickens, he turned from an analysis of the inheritance of individual traits to patterns of inheritance in populations. Recognizing, as Mendelian theory predicted, that individuals often did not express the same traits as their parents, Pearl began to study population-level characteristics such as birth rate, death rate, and population size, and to reconceptualize the genetic and environmental dynamics of evolutionary change. His work took him variously into a reanalysis of Malthus' predictions on population density and into direct conflict with the tendencies of much eugenic research to focus on individual traits and individual couples. By 1915, his reputation had grown widely enough in scientific circles to merit election to the American Philosophical Society and, in 1916, to the National Academy of Sciences.
Leaving Maine to become Professor of Biometry at Johns Hopkins in 1918, Pearl entered into the most productive period of his career. At Hopkins, where he served variously as Professor of Biology (1923-1940) and as statistician at the Johns Hopkins Hospital (1919-1935), Pearl turned a statistical eye toward the dynamics of human populations, producing remarkably accurate and durable estimates of changes in world population based upon the best-guess estimates for birth rate and longevity. More controversially, based upon U.S. Census data from 1920, he and Lowell J. Reed theorized that the logistic (sigmoidal) curve was in effect a law of nature describing population growth: after a slow initial period of expansion, populations enter a phase of exponential growth until the they reach the carrying capacity of the environment and level off. Although recognized as a useful heuristic for exploring population dynamics, Pearl's aggressive promotion of the logistic curve and his truculence in its defence alienated many of his colleagues. In other research, Pearl experimented with the factors influencing population dynamics in Drosophila melanogaster, turned to estimates of life expectancy based upon occupation and personal habits, and entered into various statistical aspects of reproductive behavior. An inveterate opponent of most eugenic policies, and critic of eugenic research, he was nevertheless a strong and vocal supporter of birth control and population planning.
Using funds provided by the Rockefeller Foundation, Pearl established the Institute for Biological Research at Johns Hopkins in 1925, heading it throughout its five year existence. He was also active in numerous professional organizations, serving as president of the International Union for Scientific Investigation of Population Problems (1928-1931), the American Association of Physical Anthropologists (1934-1936), and the American Statistical Association (1939),and helping to found and edit the Quarterly Review of Biology in 1926 and Human Biology in 1929. An agile and prolific writer, Pearl wrote 17 books and nearly 700 articles during his career on a extraordinary range of subjects.
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
Adelmann, Howard B. Correspondence (23 items) 1932-1936
Alpatov, Vladimir Vladimirovich Correspondence (52 items) 1926-1940
Alvarez, Walter C. Correspondence (40 items) 1925-1942
American Association of Physical Anthropologists Records (8 folders) 1937-1940
American Scientific Congress. Eighth Congress Records (6 folders) 1939-1940
American Statistical Association Records (4 folders) 1921-1925
Ames, Joseph S. Correspondence (22 items) 1926-1932
Association against the Prohibiton Amendment Correspondence (26 items) 1922-1930
Association for the Defense of the Constitution Correspondence (2 folders) 1935-1936
Baily, Joshua L., Jr. Correspondence (36 items) 1926-1940
Baltimore Sun Correspondence (46 items) 1928-1939
Bateson, William N. Correspondence (21 items) 1905-1924
Bell, James F. Correspondence (11 folders) 1919-1939
Berkson, Joseph Correspondence (4 folders) 1926-1940
Bernard, Leon Correspondence (66 items) 1928-1931
Biological Abstracts Correspondence (71 items) 1925-1938
Birth Control Federation of America Correspondence (3 folders) 1931-1940
Campbell, James A. Correspondence (76 items) 1906-1940
Clark, George G. Correspondence (34 items) 1913-1929
Cobb, W. Montague Correspondence (37 items) 1937-1940
Cole, Leon Jacob Correspondence (230 items) 1900-1929
Cox, Eugene A. Correspondence (46 items) 1929-1940
Crew, Francis Albert Eley Correspondence (51 items) 1921-1938
Dartmouth College Correspondence (2 folders) 1933-1940
Darwin, Leonard Correspondence (13 items) 1918-1924
DeKruif, Paul H. Correspondence (102 items) 1913-1940
DePorte, Joseph V. Correspondence (52 items) 1925-1940
Dial Correspondence (35 items) 1904-1920
East, Edward Murray Correspondence (270 items) 1911-1931
Embree, Edwin R. Correspondence (167 items) 1924-1930
Encyclopedia Britannica Correspondence (2 folders) 1925-1927
Fisher, Arne Correspondence (76 items) 1925-1939
Friede-Andreeff, Margaret Correspondence (49 items) 1909-1928
Gaskell, Augusta Correspondence (44 items) 1928-1939
Gause, Georgii Frantsevitch Correspondence (37 items) 1930-1941
Gini, Corrado Correspondence (124 items) 1927-1931
Gowen, John W. Correspondence (67 items) 1930-1940
Greenwood, Major Correspondence (506 items) 1921-1944
Harrison, Ross Granville Correspondence (133 items) 1916-1941
Henderson, Lawrence J. Correspondence (279 items) 1914-1940
Hoover, Herbert Correspondence (21 items) 1917-1940
Howard, William T. Correspondence (103 items) 1919-1939
Huhn, Rudolf von Correspondence (58 items) 1919-1929
Hurst, Fannie Correspondence (46 items) 1923-1934
Indiana University Correspondence (61 items) 1937-1940
International Institute of Statistics Records (249 items) 1937-1940
International Union for the Scientific Investigation of Population Problems Correspondence (398 items) 1925-1939
Jackson, Stuart W. Correspondence (56 items) 1934-1939
Jennings, Herbert Spencer Correspondence (249 items) 1899-1929
Johns Hopkins University Correspondence (55 items) 1919-1929
Jones, Bassett Correspondence (105 items) 1932-1940
Kelly, Fred C. Correspondence (124 items) 1919-1940
LeBlanc, Thomas J. Correspondence (60 items) 1925-1933
Lotka, Alfred J. Correspondence (318 items) 1921-1940
Mallet, Sir Bernard Correspondence (333 items) 1927-1931
Mencken, Henry Louis Correspondence (509 items) 1923-1948
Morgan, Thomas Hunt Correspondence (64 items) 1911-1931
National Academy of Sciences Correspondence (135 items) 1919-1924
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Correspondence (85 items) 1927-1933
National Research Council Correspondence (57 items) 1923-1925
Pearl, Ida May McDuffee Correspondence (138 items) 1895-1934
Pearl, Maud Mary DeWitt Correspondence (527 items) 1901-1929
Pearl, Penelope Correspondence (40 items) 1930-1942
Pearl, Raymond -- Aims and problems of the Department of Biology and their development Manuscripts (1 folder) 1935
Pearl, Raymond -- Diaries Diaries (44 volumes) 1902-1940
Pearl, Raymond -- Laboratory notebooks Notebooks (2 volumes) 1930-1931
Pearl, Raymond Scrapbooks (10 volumes) 1919-1940
Pearson, Karl Correspondence (141 items) 1901-1937
Population Association of America Correspondence (61 items) 1934-1936
Quarterly Review of Biology Correspondence (47 items) 1927-1940
Rockefeller Foundation Correspondence (55 items) 1930-1936
Rockefeller Institute of Medical Research Correspondence (74 items) 1931-1934
Russell, Edward Stuart Correspondence (64 items) 1934-1944
Saint John's College Correspondence (229 items) 1928-1936
Sanger, Margaret Correspondence (390 items) 1921-1935
Social Science Research Council Correspondence (132 items) 1928-1930
Social Science Research Council. Advisory Committee on Population Correspondence (36 items) 1928-1930
Stefansson, Vilhjalmur Correspondence (299 items) 1919-1939
Surface, Frank M. Correspondence (51 items) 1910-1923
Sweeney, James Shirley Correspondence (67 items) 1923-1932
Thomas, Charles C. Correspondence (156 items) 1927-1932
Walcott, Frederic C. Correspondence (63 items) 1919-1938
Welch, William H. Correspondence (141 items) 1916-1932
Wheeler, William Morton Correspondence (243 items) 1910-1937
Willcox, Walter F. Correspondence (158 items) 1922-1940
Williams, Ira Jewell, Jr. Correspondence (143 items) 1925-1941
Wilson, Edwin Bidwell Correspondence (242 items) 1922-1936
Wing, Leonard W. Correspondence (45 items) 1939
Winsor, Charles P. Correspondence (66 items) 1926-1936
Wislocki, George B. Correspondence (54 items) 1931-1940
Woods, Charles D. Correspondence (110 items) 1906-1925
Yerkes, Robert M. Correspondence (86 items) 1903-1929
Yule, George Udny Correspondence (155 items) 1903-1944
American Association of Physical Anthropologists.; Baltimore Sun; Bell, James F.; Berkson, Joseph, 1899-; Bernard, Léon, b. 1877; Birth Control Federation of America.; Campbell, James A., 1917-; Cox, Eugene A.; Dartmouth College; East, Edward M., (Edward Murray), 1879-1938; Embree, Edwin R., (Edwin Rogers), 1883-1950; Fisher, Arne; Gini, Corrado, 1884-; Greenwood, Major, 1880-; Harrison, Ross G., (Ross Granville), 1870-1959; International Statistical Institute.; Jones, Bassett, 1877-1960; Mallet, Bernard, Sir; Mencken, H. L., (Henry Louis), 1880-1956; Morgan, Thomas Hunt, 1866-1945; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.); Pearl, Ida May McDuffee; Pearl, Maud Mary DeWitt; Pearson, Karl, 1857-1936; Ritter, William Emerson, 1856-1944; Russell, E. S. (Edward Stuart), 1887-1954; Sanger, Margaret, 1879-1966; Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1879-1962; Sweeney, James Shirley, 1896-; The Quarterly Review of Biology.; Thomas, Charles C., 1925-; Walcott, Frederic Collin, 1869-1949; Wheeler, William Morton, 1865-1937; Willcox, Walter Francis, 1861-1964; Wilson, Edwin Bidwell, 1879-1964; Yerkes, Robert Mearns, 1876-1956; Yule, G. Udny, (George Udny), 1871-1951; Biology; Biology publishing; Biology, genetics, eugenics; Biology--Periodicals; Biometry; Birth control.; Culture, community, organizations; Diaries.; Eugenics; Evolution (Biology); Genetics; Human evolution; Population biology; Race, race relations, racism; Science publishing.; Social conditions, social advocacy, social reform; Statistics; World War, 1914-1918
- Series I. Correspondence
  Scope and Contents note
  Reflecting Pearl's interests in the biometric study of human populations, the collection includes abundant correspondence relating to statistics, human evolution, demography, longevity, and birth control, but the topics covered in correspondence are very diverse. Among the most prolific correspondents were his antagonist, E. M. East (1879-1938), Leon J. Cole (b. 1877), Herbert Spencer Jennings (1868-1947), Alfred J. Lotka (1880-1949), Major Greenwood (b. 1880), T.H. Morgan, Margaret Sanger (1879-1966), Vilhjalmur Stefansson (1879-1962), William Henry Welch (1850-1934), E. B. Wilson, William Morton Wheeler (1865-1937), Corado Gini (b. 1881), Karl Pearson (1857-1936), Bernard Mallet (1859-1932), Robert Mearns Yerkes (1876-1956), and George Udny Yule (b.1871). The series of letters between Pearl and his friend H. L. Mencken (1880-1956), including several written at the time of the Scopes "monkey trial," are of particular interest.
  Pearl's opposition to eugenics earned him both friends and adversaries (most notable among the latter, E.M. East), as reflected throughout the collection. His correspondence with East and Cole, Jennings, Pearson, the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, I.J. Williams, E.B. Wilson, F.A.E. Crew, the Rockefeller Institute, and W.T. Howard (among others) touches frequently on issues of genetics, eugenics, race, and human evolution.
  Finally, the collection includes one linear foot of correspondence between Pearl and his mother, Ida, and his wife, Maud.
  - Abbott, E. A. (Box 1)
  - Abel, J. (Box 1)
  - Acta Biotheoretica (Box 1)
    Klauuw, C. J. van der
  - Adams, Charles C. (Box 1)
  - Adams, Samuel Hopkins (Box 1)
  - Adams, Thomas (Box 1)
  - Adelmann, Howard B., 1932-1936; 23 items (Box 1)
    Editorial matters; Publication
  - Agar, W. E. (Box 1)
  - Aims and Problems of the Department of Biology, and Their Development, 31 March 1935; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940 (Box 1)
    Biographical and personal data; Johns Hopkins University; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Allard and Sons (Box 1)
  - Allee, W. C. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Bennet M. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Glover M. (Box 1)
  - Alpatov, W. W. (Vladimir Vladimirovich), 1926-1940; 52 items (Box 1)
    Biographical and personal data; Fellowships, assistantships; Genetics; Physiology; Publication; Recommendations -- Gause, Georgii Frantsevitch; Recommendations -- Park, Thomas; Russian politics and science; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Alvarez, Walter C., 1925-1942; 40 items (Box 1)
    Biographical and personal data; Cancer, chemotherapy; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Medical research; Publication; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - American Adding Machine (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science. Committee of One Hundred (Box 1)
    Pupin, Michael I.
    True, Rodney H.
  - American Association of Physical Anthropologists, 1937-1940; 8 folders (Box 1)
    Shapiro, H. L.
    Hooten, E. A.
    Hrdlicka, Ales
    Howells, W. W.
    Krogman, W. M.
    Terry, R. J.
    Todd, T. Wingate
    Barnum, Irena
    Field, Henry
    Todd, Eleanor Wingate
    Stewart, T. Dale
    Montagu, Ashley
    Farris, Edmond J.
    Greene, J. E.
    Anthropology -- Anthropometry; Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Eugenics; Honors -- Hrdlicka, Ales; Human evolution, physical anthropology; International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Science -- Committee on Standardization of Technique of Anthropometry; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1937 - January 1938 (Box 1)
    - Folder 2, February 1938 - April 1938 (Box 1)
    - Folder 3, May 1938 - December 1938 (Box 1)
    - Folder 4, January 1939 - February 1939 (Box 1)
    - Folder 5, March 1939 (Box 1)
    - Folder 6, April 1939 - August 1939 (Box 1)
    - Folder 7, September 1939 - December 1939 (Box 1)
    - Folder 8, 1940 (Box 1)
  - American Book Company (Box 1)
    Brigstock, F. S.
  - American Breeders' Association (Box 1)
  - American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom (Box 1)
    Boas, Franz
  - American Express Company (Box 1)
  - American Journal of Botany (Box 1)
    Gager, C. Stuart
    Allen, C. E.
    Jordan, William E.
  - American Journal of Science (Box 1)
  - American Medical Association (Box 1)
    Puckner, W. A.
    Leech, Paul Nicholas
  - American Physicians' Art Association (Box 1)
  - American Society of Ichthyologists and Herpetologists (Box 1)
    Netting, M. Graham
  - American Statistical Association, 1921-1925; 4 folders (Box 1)
    Chaddock, Robert E.
    Ogburn, William F.
    Rossiter, William S.
    Andrew, S. L.
    Editorial matters; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics
  - Ames, Joseph S., 1926-1932; 22 items (Box 1)
    Biographical and personal data; Johns Hopkins University -- Institute for Biological Research; Rockefeller Foundation
  - Andrews, E. A. (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Eliza Frances (Box 1)
  - Andrews, James M. (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Justin (Box 1)
  - Angon, J. B. (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Printing Company (Box 1)
  - Annals of Eugenics (Box 1)
    Fisher, R. A.
    Karn, M. N.
  - Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Sciences (Box 2)
  - Annual Review of Biochemistry (Box 2)
    Luck, J. Murray
  - Anthonisen, Margaret R. (Box 2)
  - Anthropologischer Anzeiger (Box 2)
    Gieseler, W.
    Vogel, G.
    Mollison, Th.
  - Appel, Fred and Elizabeth (Box 2)
  - Ark, P. A. (Box 2)
  - Armsty, H. P. (Box 2)
  - Association Against the Prohibition Amendment, 1922-1930; 26 items (Box 2)
    Stayton, W. H.
    DuPont, P. S.
    Hinckley, G. C.
    Poe, Philip L.
    Political issues; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Association for the Defense of the Constitution, 1935-1936; 2 folders (Box 2)
    Political issues
    - Folder 1 (Box 2)
      Cahn, Frank B.
    - Folder 2 (Box 2)
      Burnett, Paul M.
  - Athenaeum of London (Box 2)
  - Atkinson, Reginald (Box 2)
  - Atterbury, Howard (Box 2)
  - Atwood, William T. (Box 2)
  - Austrian, Charles R. (Box 2)
  - Aznoe's National Physicians' Exchange (Box 2)
  - Bachmetjen, P. (Box 2)
  - Bacon, Clara L. (Box 2)
  - Baerg, W. J. (Box 2)
  - Baetjer, Edward G (Box 2)
  - Bailey, Frank W. (Box 2)
  - Bailey, Irving W. (Box 2)
  - Baily, Joshua L., Jr., 1926-1940; 36 items (Box 2)
    Biographical and personal data; Graduate study; Johns Hopkins University; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Zoology
  - Baily, Ruth Ingersoll (Box 2)
  - Baker, Mary W. (Box 2)
  - Baker, Lawrence H. (Box 2)
  - Balamuth, William (Box 2)
  - Balfour, Andrew (Box 2)
  - Balinsky, B. I. (Box 2)
  - Baltimore Sun, 1928-1939; 2 folders (46 items) (Box 2)
    Political issues; Publication -- Baltimore Sun; Reviews; Saturday Night Club
    - Folder 1 (Box 2)
      Wagner, Philip
      Walcott, F. C.
      Ward, Paul W.
      Beirne, Frank F.
      Owens, John M.
      Fitzpatrick, Edwin A.
    - Folder 2 (Box 2)
      Owens, John W.
      Watson, Mark
      Hyde, Henry M.
      Owens, Hamilton
  - Barbour, Thomas (Box 2)
  - Bardeen, Charles R. (Box 2)
  - Barker, Lewellys F. (Box 2)
  - Barnard, Chester I. (Box 2)
  - Barr, Mark W. (Box 2)
  - Barstow (Box 2)
  - Bateson, William, 1905-1924; 21 items (Box 2)
    Biographical and personal data; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Fifth Congress; Invitations; Poultry genetics
  - Baür, Erwin (Box 2)
  - Bauer, Julius (Box 2)
  - Bauernschmidt, Mrs. Marie O. von H. (Box 2)
  - Bausch and Lomb Optical Company (Box 2)
  - Bayard, E. S. (Box 2)
  - Beal, Kenneth (Box 2)
  - Beardsley, E. J. G. (Box 2)
  - Becking, L. B. (Box 2)
  - Beckwith, Cora J. (Box 2)
  - Beecher, Peck and Lewis (Box 2)
  - Bell, Alexander Graham (Box 2)
  - Bell, Ford (Box 2)
  - Bell, James F., 1919-1939; 11 folders (Box 2-3)
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Political issues; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1 (Box 2)
      Griggs, Cooper, and Company
      Crosby, John
      Bell, Samuel, Jr.
    - Folder 2 (Box 2)
    - Folder 3 (Box 2)
      Haugen, G. B.
    - Folder 4 (Box 2)
    - Folder 5 (Box 3)
      Bateson, W.
      Baur, Erwin
      Darwin, Leonard
      Gini, Corrado
      Punnett, R. C.
      Yule, G. Udny
    - Folder 6 (Box 3)
      Davis, D. D.